Guide to the Stanford University, Department of Political Science, Honors Theses SC4-4493
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Theses, 1987, 1991; Accession ARCH-1992-100
  - Roszkewycz, Roman Matthew, Ukrainian nationalism: the problem of collectivizing agriculture in the Soviet Ukraine., May 1991 (Box 4)
  - Ryan, Kristine, A revised perception of PACs in politics., May 1991 (Box 4)
  - Spander, Deborah, German Reunification and Antisemitism: A Political View., June 1991 (Box 4)
  - Su, Julie Ann, Chinatown Youth in the Promised Land: American Dream -- Or American Nightmare?., 1991 (Box 4)
  - Tankel, Jason E., Anglophone and Francophone Black Africa: Colonial Legacies and Politcal Stability., June 1991 (Box 4)
  - Vergara, James A. Kostohryz, The Challenges of Economic Liberalization in Mexico., 1991 (Box 4)
  - White, Kenneth P., Issues in the Restriction of Racist Speech., May 1991 (Box 4)
- Theses, 1992; Accession ARCH-1993-079
  - Breslin, Kelly, British Civil Rights and Civil Liberties: A Closer Look., 1992 (Box 1)
  - Brida, Tom, The Organizaion of Farm Workers in California., 1992 (Box 1)
  - Garcia, Ruben J., The Politics of the new braceros: the influence of agricultural interests on the Temporary Worker programs of the 1986 Immigration Reform and control act of 1992. (Box 1)
  - Hungerford, Andrea, The politics of environmentalism., 1992 (Box 1)
  - Forman, Mark, The Origins of Cold War Public Opinion: An Examination of Opinion Leadership During the Truman Administration's First Sixteen Months, 1992; 1 folder(s)
  - Laris, Michael, Pushing out the boundaries in China's Media., 1992 (Box 1)
  - Liu, Dorothy S., The nonelectoral politics of the Chinese in America., 1992 (Box 1)
  - Melhorn, Dimitri, Anarchy: a contemporary model., 1992 (Box 1)
  - Robinson, Vincent J., Community-based bureaucracy: vying for resources in San Francisco's AIDS community., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Rosenwasser, Jon J., The role of economic relations in fighting the Cold War: Washington's and Bonn's Approach., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Rush, Melissa Jo, The Senate vote on Justice Clarence Thomas: the eleven democratic senators who voted to confirm and the two Republican senators who voted to oppose., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Saul, Leslie C., The INF difference: coming to terms with the technical utility of on-site inspection., 1990 (Box 2)
  - Wallen, Madeline Sue, Reform Efforts for the Battered Women: The Different Approaches of Reformers from Different Periods., 1992 (Box 2)
- Theses, 1994-1998; Accession ARCH-2000-180
  - Baily, Melissa J., The Kyoto Protocol on Climate Change: A Case Study for the Theoretical Explanation of the Disparity Between the Policy Positions of the United States and he European Union in International Environmental Negotiations., June 1998 (Box 1)
  - Barnes, Jeffrey E., Public Opinion and International Relations: The Paralysis of U.S. Foreign Policy During Periods of Global Transitions., 1995 (Box 1)
  - Batchelder, Lily, The Incorporation Movement of East Palo Alto: Renegotiating the Boundaries of Community Organizing Theory., May 1994 (Box 1)
  - Beasley, Duane K., Town and Gown: Can the University Save the City?., May 1996 (Box 1)
  - Beverly, Alaina C., Race-Xenophobia: An Analysis of British and Caribbean Immigration in the Post-World War II Era., May 1998 (Box 1)
  - Bianchini, Gina, The Success of Head Start, Why Head Start Continued when the Great Society Failed., May 1994 (Box 1)
  - Cheng, Chi-Mei, The Challenge to the Model Minority Myth: Juvenile Delinquency Among Chinese Americans., Spring 1995 (Box 1)
  - Childs, Jennifer, A Tactical Error in the War on Drugs: Injustices of the Mandatory Minimum Sentencing Scheme., May 1994 (Box 1)
  - Chung, Edwin, Barriers to Asian Americans' Political Inclusion: The Emergence of a "No-Man's Land" Theory., Spring 1998 (Box 1)
  - Doolittle, Cameron M., Origins of (Political) Species: State Legislatures as the Supply Side of U.S. Congressional Candidate Emergence., May 1998 (Box 1)
  - Edwards, Barry, Taming Militarism Through Law., May 1995 (Box 2)
  - Eichenbaum, Lindy B., From Lincoln-Douglas to Kerry-Weld: An Economic Theory Explaining the Degeneration of Political Debates., Undated (Box 2)
  - Everson, Ann, The Demigod Authority: Justice, Power, and Social Control in Four Shakespearean Comedies., May 1995 (Box 2)
  - Fang, June F., Institutions Revisited: A Case Study of the Medicare Home Health Benefit and Dynamics Behind Program Expansion., May 1995 (Box 2)
  - Feng, Lillian, A Criticism of "Three Strikes and You're Out"., May 1995 (Box 2)
  - Garza, Sergio, Democracia Ya? Consolidating Political Opposition in Mexico's Party of the Democratic Revolution., May 1995 (Box 2)
  - Gerber, Scott Charles, Indirect Counsel: More's Utopia as Practical Philosophy., May 1997 (Box 2)
  - Gibson, Chanda, The community as care givers: Can they cope with Zimbabwe's Orphan Crisis?., May 1995 (Box 2)
  - Giordani, Sonia M., Mass Media and the transformation of Democratic Society: The Rise of Berlusconian Politics in Italy., Spring 1996 (Box 2)
  - Goodman, Joseph W., Pervasive corruption in the NYPD: The case for a permanent external monitor., May 1995 (Box 2)
  - Griggs, John J., Economic Analysis of Intellectual property regimes in east-central Europe. (Box 2)
  - Hamill, Cameron H., President Clinton's National Service Initiative., May 1994 (Box 3)
  - Haskovec, Alexandra S., The Demise of the German Welfare State? The Future of Welfare in the 1990s and Beyond., May 1995 (Box 3)
  - Heidelberg, Falona, Cultural Power: the defining of University., June 1998 (Box 3)
  - Herman, Burt, Will Democracy survive? freedom of the press in post-communist Romania., May 1995 (Box 3)
  - Herthel, Jason S., The politics of advice and consent: divided government and the appointment of justices to the United States Supreme Court., March 1997 (Box 3)
  - Higuchi, Beatriz, The misuse of ambiguity: The single currency non-debate in France., May 1997 (Box 3)
  - Jennings, Katie, British appeasement, from Versailles to Munich: a policy of peace, a path to war., May 1997 (Box 3)
  - John, Melind J., Hate Crime Laws: Resolving the Moral, legal, and political dilemmas posed by sentence enhancement statutes, hate speech codes, and other laws enacted to remedy hate motivated crime., May 1994 (Box 3)
  - Johnson, Jimmie, FDR and the new confidence., May 1998 (Box 3)
  - Kane, Brian A., The move to federation: 1787 America and modern-day Europe., May 1995 (Box 4)
  - Kim, Lauren S., Reexamining Judicial interpretation of Heartbalm statutes and actions., May 1995 (Box 4)
  - Kula, Wendy N., The Somalie Syndrome: Understanding the limits of Media Influence., May 1996 (Box 4)
  - Kun, Deborah E., The state's responsibilty for punishment: evaluating the practice of prison and jail privatization., May 1995 (Box 4)
  - Lee, Patricia C., Emerging Federalism in Post-Mao China; the impact of foreign trade and investment policies., May 1994 (Box 4)
  - Lefler, Solomon, The politics of cultural values in Singapore: explaining the PAP's East/West dichotomy., May 1998 (Box 4)
  - Levine, Jonathan I., Rethinking Our conception of immigration: the challenge of Proposition 187., June 1996 (Box 4)
  - Magliocca, Gerard N., Islam on the March: A Model of Iranian Foreign Policy., May 1995 (Box 5)
  - Malone, Edward, Black Americans divored the Republican party. Will the same thing happen to the Democrats., May 1995 (Box 5)
  - Marcum, Arthur J., Coping with free trade: US Organized labor emerging Post-NAFTA strategy., May 1995 (Box 5)
  - Marshak, Rachel K., Restraining the sovereign: an integration of the democracy and the democratization literature., May 1998 (Box 5)
  - Massahos, Debera L., Patchwork, Power, and politics: quilt groups of the civial war Era become effective political associations. (Box 5)
  - Matsui, Brian R., The politics of reelection versus the politics of Change: congressional reform in House of Representatives., May 1995 (Box 5)
  - McBride, Abigail B., The role of broadcast media in the presidential primary process: a question of influence., May 1997 (Box 5)
  - McGhee, Eric, Racial representation int he United States: A Comparative political perspective., May 1995 (Box 5)
  - McMillion, Barry J., Acting for women: the substantive representation of Women's interests during the 103rd Congress., Winter 1995 (Box 5)
  - Mervis, Ari, International election monitoring: a case study analysis of the factors that influence the accuracy of observer missions., May 1997 (Box 6)
  - Morse, Jessica, Do we need women to represent women's interests? An exploration of the representation of women's interests in the U. S. House of Representatives., June 1995 (Box 6)
  - Mukamal, Ari, The Official Secrets Acts 1889-1989: The History and Persistence of a Controversial Law., March 1997 (Box 6)
  - Murapa, Tau C., Alfred Thayer Mahan in perspective: A theory of naval power for the twenty-first century., June 1998 (Box 6)
  - Nazemi, Mina P., Understanding the sturggles of Mexican and Latino janitors at Stanford University and use of unions as a method of empowerment., June 1998 (Box 6)
  - Neiman, Elizabeth D., Compromising compensatory education: an organizational study in the implementation of ESEA., May 1994 (Box 6)
  - Nellis, Nahalel, Bureaucratic Efficiency in South Korea in the Park Administration., May 1996 (Box 6)
  - Nishi, Takayuki, Systematic change and military technology transfer., May 1996 (Box 6)
  - Perry, Tina M., A comparative analysis of US employment discrimination policy and British anti-discrimination legislation., June 1994 (Box 7)
  - Quintana, Luz, Majority Will v. Minority Rights: Proposition 187b and the Latino Community., May 1995 (Box 7)
  - Rajgopal, Kausik, The treaty on nuclear non-proliferation institutional design, issue linkage, and domestic politics., May 1995 (Box 7)
  - Randazzo, John B., Liberalism and the religious fundamentalist., May 1995 (Box 7)
  - Rooney, Amie D., Interaction and Response: Avoiding Response: Avoiding overrides of Supreme Court Statutory Decisions., May 1998 (Box 7)
  - Ross, Adam B., Southern Politics: explaining the GOP lag in Congress since 1948., June 1995 (Box 7)
  - Schar, Reid J., Murder, Journalism, and American Society at the Turn of the Century., March 1994 (Box 7)
  - Shahani, Annik Rene, Integration and Disintegration in Regional Integration Schemes; the Triumph of the European Community and the Tragedy of the Latin American Free Trade Association., June 1994 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Anastasia M., Unequal Protection: Racial Disparities in the 1986 Anti-Drug Abuse Act., June 1997 (Box 7)
  - Stabrowski, Filip, Whither Solidarity? Analyzing the Polish Workers' Movement of 1980-81 and Pondering its Existence in Post-Communist Poland., May 1997 (Box 8)
  - Stephenson, Cameron W., Illegal Immigration Policy: the Inherent Impairments of the American Policymaking Process., May 1996 (Box 8)
  - Svilik, Victor, The United States Court of International Trade: A Study of Strategic Interaction between Industry, the Bureaucracy and the Judiciary in the Adminstration of U.S. Trade Law., May 1995 (Box 8)
  - Tai, Mae, Japanese Housing Policy within the Iron Triangle; the Treatment of Housing Issues under the Liberal Democratic Party., May 1994 (Box 8)
  - Thompson, Kim, American Multilateral Military Intervention in the Post-Cold War World., June 1994 (Box 8)
  - Tippins, Clay, Prospects for a Fourth Constitutional Regime., May 1995 (Box 8)
  - Toshav, Effie, Bad Medicine: Human Radiation Experiments Conducted at the University of California in San Francisco., May 1995 (Box 8)
  - Truesdale, Joseph R., The Fragmented State of East Central Europe: Nationalism and the Dissolution of Czechoslovakia., 1996 (Box 8)
  - Tusan, Christina V., Homeless Families in America From 1980-1994: Casualties of Declining Governmental Support for the War on Poverty., May 1994 (Box 8)
  - Vick, Kevin, Norplant Incentives and Women on Welfare., 1996? (Box 8)
  - Vynalek, Christopher B., Facade of Grandeur: The Move to the Median., 1995 (Box 8)
  - Wadhwa, Kul, The New Media: The Rise and Implementation of Entertainment Channels in the American Political Campaign., 1994 (Box 9)
  - Wang, Rosalind, Just War Theory and the Ethics of Roman War., May 1997 (Box 9)
  - Weintraub, Jason, Building a Meritocracy: The Use of the LSAT in Law School Admissions., May 1996 (Box 9)
  - Weintraub, Scott, Dead Man Walking: Racial Discrimination and the Unconstitutionality of the Death Penalty., May 1996 (Box 9)
  - Werlich, M. Katja, Ethnic Conflict and International Relations; A Rational Perspective., March 1996 (Box 9)
  - Wong, Melissa, A Moral Defense of Legalized Abortion: Applying John Rawl's "Justice as Fairness" to the Abortion Controversy., May 1995 (Box 9)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Allen, Tracy, Calm, controversy, conflict: the selection and confirmation of Supreme Court justices in the modern era., 1992 (Box 1)
  - Berglund, Katherine H., A nuclear impasse: an analysis of the U.S.-Iranian nuclear debate., 2005 (Box 1)
  - Bodnar, Paul, Institutional design and the politics of uncertainty: case studies in East European democratization., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Flowers, Kobie Alan, The paradox of prison reform., 1994 (Box 1)
  - Gair, Abby Jean, Civil liberties and war: the social learning process., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Lucero, José Antonio, A harsh paradox: the impact of Hernandez v. New York., 1994 (Box 1)
  - Marshak, Rachel Kolman, Restraining the sovereign: an integration of the democracy and the democratization literature., 1998 (Box 2)
  - Penny, Melanie Rose, Criminal distortion: the culpability of the media in the disparate incarceration of African-American youth., 2002 (Box 2)
  - Podolsky, Ryan T., US efforts to promote democracy in transitional polities: the case of Kyrgyzstan., 2005 (Box 2)
  - Popp, Noah H., The appearance of money in politics: the impact of campaign finance reform on public attitudes towards corruption., 2004 (Box 2)
  - Prabhu, Sarita, Seeing eye to eye: the representaiton of Black interests in majority-white districts., 2003 (Box 2)
  - Schwartz, Victoria, The influence of the West on the 1993 Russian Constitution., 2004 (Box 2)
  - Stamm, Lindsay J., A comparative study of gold mining practices and NGO monitoring in Indonesia, the US and Peru., 2000 (Box 2)
  - Winant, Gabriel, Can't win them all: Congressional party organization and strategy in the era of the contested majority., 2008 (Box 2)
  - Yu, Wai-Yin Alice, Legal imperialism in Hong Kong, 1841-1860., 2000 (Box 2)
  - Stoll, Nathan W., Economic voting and individual values in cross-national perspective., 2002 (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Brandis C., The "race" to color-blindness: examining the policy implications of the Racial Privacy Initiative in California., 2003 (Box 3)
  - Baran, Zeyno, Turkey after the 1980s: are Islam and democracy compatible?., 1996 (Box 3)
  - Cheung, Jenny W., Recall: what Madison should have said., 2004 (Box 3)
  - Dalal, Payal, At home in an other world., 2003 (Box 3)
  - Gleason, Nicholas A., The alliance process of the PS and PDC during Chile's authoritarian regime., 1990 (Box 3)
  - Hatamiya, Leslie T., Righting a wrong: the passage of the Civil Liberties Act of 1988., 1990 (Box 3)
  - Kim, Angela S., Racial disparities in the criminal justice system: McCleskey v. Kemp and its aftermath., 1990 (Box 3)
  - Murphy, Alan, Regionalism and the suburban voter., 2003 (Box 3)
  - Nagareda, Richard A., Justice and the judicial role: contemporary interpretations of the Fourteenth Amendment., 1985 (Box 4)
  - Shannon, Patrick K., Burke on moral revolution., 1986 (Box 4)
  - Loughran, Julie, The political economy of Southeast Asian development: a comparative analysis with implications for dependency theory., 1990 (Box 4)
  - Paxton, Laura, Towards the end of impunity: the British extradition proceedings against Pinochet to Spain., 2000 (Box 4)
  - Hendelman, Aaron D., The role of the Bush Administration in the passage of the Civil Rights Act of 1991., 1993 (Box 4)
  - Ranese, Thomas F. Jr., Politics and the arts: evidence of a dialectic. The Arts Council and the dramatic form in Great Britain., 1993 (Box 4)
  - Rowley, Fred A. Jr., Politics and justice: a study of Hannah Arendt's political journey., 1993 (Box 4)
  - Nixon, Hamish A. D., Engineered transition: the politics of international intervention in Cambodia., 1995 (Box 4)
  - Chung, Kevin F., Equal employment opportunity testing: a constitutional and effective weapon in the fight against employment discrimination., 1993? (Box 4)
  - Schwartz, David R., The politics of judicial selection: advice, consent, and the Supreme Court nomination of Ruth Bader Ginsberg., 1994 (Box 5)
  - Lifur, Jeff, Democratic transition and consolidation in Chile: the role of political parties on the right., 1992 (Box 5)
  - Taylor, Brian Mitchell, A comparative analysis of the cost control and delivery systems of three industrialized countries: the United States, Canada, and Japan., 1992 (Box 5)
  - Kendall, Alexander, The joke isn't on the Democrats? The partisan effects of voter turnout., 2004 (Box 5)
  - Enion, Michael Rhead, Sexuality, expression and the First Amendment in Constitutional law., 2002 (Box 5)
  - Agarwal, Priya, Creating identities: Indian immigrant families in the United States. A study of post-1965 professional Indian immigrants and their children., 1991 (Box 5)
  - Sanchez, Micheal, Lethal injection: an analysis of the Texas death penalty., 2001 (Box 5)
  - Prabhu, Sarita, Seeing eye to eye: the representation of Black interests in majority-white districts., 2003 (Box 5)
  - Spence, Matthew J., Power, politics and restraint: judicial strategic choice and the Russian Constitutional Court., 2000 (Box 5)
  - Rosen, Candace Jaclyn, Sexual harrassment and Title VII: an inadequate remedy., 1993 (Box 6)
  - Randazzo, John Bruno, Liberalism and the religious fundamentalist., 1995 (Box 6)
  - Elford, Joseph, The egalitarian minimalist state., 1993 (Box 6)
  - Kun, Deborah E., The State's responsibility for punishment: evaluating the practice of prison and jail privatization., 1995 (Box 6)
  - von Lohmann, Fred, It ain't what it seems: explaining Congressional activity on abortion since 1973., 1990 (Box 6)
  - Killian, Wendelyn P., Black electoral strategies and successes in the 1980s: case studies of Harold Washington and Jesse Jackson with implications for the 1990s., 1994 (Box 6)
  - Thompson, Kim, American multilateral military intervention in the post-Cold War world., 1994 (Box 6)
  - Calleros, Russell Amador, Improving race relations in Los Angeles through political means., 1994 (Box 6)
  - Perry, Tina Marie, A comparative analysis of US employment discrimination policy and British anti-discrimination legislation., 1994 (Box 6)
  - Haskovec, Alexandra S., The demise of the German welfare state? The future of welfare in the 1990s and beyond., 1995 (Box 6)
  - Stephenson, Blake, The coming revolution in intellectual property., 1994 (Box 6)
  - Abdullah, Sharifah, A tale of two inner cities: the Los Angeles riots of 1992 and the Brixton riots of 1981., 1997 (Box 6)
  - Kula, Wendy Nicole, The Somalia syndrome: understanding the limits of media influence., 1996 (Box 6)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2018-060
  - Hanson, Kolby, "Victory, democracy and survival", 2011 (Box 1)